<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coding In The Open</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Coding In The Open</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://codingedi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arfon Smith - Journal of Open Source: Where Open Source meets academic peer review</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/arfon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/arfon/</guid><description>I’m a Staff Product Manager for Data at GitHub, supporting the work of our data science and data engineering teams. Previously, I founded and led the Data Science Mission Office at STScI in Baltimore – the home of Hubble Space Telescope and other flagship NASA science missions. For those of you paying attention, you might have noticed that I was at GitHub once before (2013–2016), helping to bring open source to academia.</description></item><item><title>Kirstie Whitaker - The Turing Way: Empowering researchers in reproducible, ethical, inclusive and collaborative science</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/kirstie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/kirstie/</guid><description>Although reproducible research is necessary to ensure that scientific work can be trusted, it requires skills in data management, library sciences, software development, and data ethics considerations: skills that are not widely taught or expected of academic researchers. Beyond these skills lie the structural and incentive barriers to working open. The Turing Way aims to provide a safe space for data scientists in academia, industry, government and the third sector to practice these skills and build open source materials covering version control, analysis testing, collaborating in distributed groups, open and transparent communication skills, and effective management of diverse research projects.</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 21:33:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/schedule/</guid><description>To be announced - stay tuned! We&amp;rsquo;ll have all the details for you very soon</description></item><item><title>Coding In The Open</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/about/</guid><description>Coding In The Open is a week of 1 hour seminars happening June 14th - 18th, online.
We aim to bring the discussion around Open Source practices - that is, the collaboration across organisations to achieve bigger things - to a new audience.
We&amp;rsquo;ve some fantastic speakers lined up from public, private, charity and academic sectors to talk about what being &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; means to them, and how it improves their world.</description></item></channel></rss>