<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coding In The Open</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Coding In The Open</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://codingedi.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arfon Smith</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/arfon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/arfon/</guid><description>Journal of Open Source: Where Open Source meets academic peer review About Arfon I’m a Staff Product Manager for Data at GitHub, supporting the work of our data science and data engineering teams. Previously, I founded and led the Data Science Mission Office at STScI in Baltimore – the home of Hubble Space Telescope and other flagship NASA science missions. For those of you paying attention, you might have noticed that I was at GitHub once before (2013–2016), helping to bring open source to academia.</description></item><item><title>Hillary Juma</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/hillary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/hillary/</guid><description>Curating community About Hillary Hillary (she/her) is Community Manager, Common Voice Project at Mozilla Foundation. Previously, Hillary was Data Science Community and Engagement Manager, Office for National Statistics’ Data Science Campus. She enjoys creating space for community by collaborating and enabling knowledge sharing between members.
Links https://commonvoice.mozilla.org/en</description></item><item><title>Kirstie Whitaker</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/kirstie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/kirstie/</guid><description>The Turing Way: Empowering researchers in reproducible, ethical, inclusive and collaborative science Although reproducible research is necessary to ensure that scientific work can be trusted, it requires skills in data management, library sciences, software development, and data ethics considerations: skills that are not widely taught or expected of academic researchers. Beyond these skills lie the structural and incentive barriers to working open. The Turing Way aims to provide a safe space for data scientists in academia, industry, government and the third sector to practice these skills and build open source materials covering version control, analysis testing, collaborating in distributed groups, open and transparent communication skills, and effective management of diverse research projects.</description></item><item><title>Sian Basker</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/sian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/sian/</guid><description>Data Maturity – A Fruitful Journey for the Not-for-Profit Sector Data Orchard works collaboratively with others to build the data capabilities of the not-for-profit sector. Since 2015 they have been researching the data maturity of organisations and openly sharing their knowledge and resources. Their free online data maturity assessment tool launched in October 2019 and has been used by hundreds of non-governmental, public sector, universities and commercial organisations. In this session, Sian Basker will reflect on how collaboration and openness have created strong roots and are beginning to produce rich fruits in knowledge and learning for advancing the sector.</description></item><item><title>David Calder</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/david/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/david/</guid><description>Developing Reproducible Analytical Pipelines with open source software improves quality and trust in official statistics Public Health Scotland is the primary producer of official statistics for the NHS in Scotland and has around 200 public releases of data each year. Production of these statistics using proprietary software can be time consuming, resource-intensive and cumbersome. Reproducible Analytical Pipelines utilises open source tools and combines data science best practice and principles to effectively automate these processes to increase auditability, efficiency and quality.</description></item><item><title>Saber Razmjooei</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/saber/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/saber/</guid><description>Making a business and a sense of place from open source Data is everywhere and without location, it is often difficult to make sense of it. With the free and open source https://inputapp.io you can collect spatial data. The app is powered by QGIS software and allows you a seamless link between mobile and desktop. Synchronisation of the data between the devices and users is done using a git-like technology.</description></item><item><title>John A Stevenson</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/john/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/john/</guid><description>Going open is a process, not an event About John Software developer + postdoc geologist tweeting volcanoes, Iceland, GIS &amp;amp; open source science software. Into climbing, mountain-biking, exploring. Husband, dad.
Links ETL Helper: https://pypi.org/project/etlhelper/ BGS GitHub: https://github.com/BritishGeologicalSurvey UKGEOS Glasgow (will feature in talk): https://ukgeos.ac.uk/observatories/glasgow</description></item><item><title>Code of Conduct</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/coc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 22:11:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/coc/</guid><description>As an event (jointly) created by the EdinbR community, we will adhere to the to the R Consortium and R Community Code of conduct.</description></item><item><title>Organisers</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/organiser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 22:11:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/organiser/</guid><description>Coding in the Open is jointly organised by EdinbR and PyData Edinburgh
EdinbR EdinbR is the Edinburgh usergroup for the R programming language, and aims to bring together scientists, statisticians and programmers from all over Edinburgh to discuss R-related matters. We encourage collaboration between local R users and organise training events for those interested in learning the language. EdinbR meets monthly (on the third Wednesday of the month) and welcomes new attendees, regardless of R knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 21:33:26 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/schedule/</guid><description>To be announced - stay tuned! We&amp;rsquo;ll have all the details for you very soon.
The event will be hosted on BlueJeans (courtesy of Red Hat) and you can sign up on Meetup.</description></item><item><title>Coding In The Open</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/about/</guid><description>Coding In The Open is a week of 1 hour seminars happening June 14th - 18th, online.
We aim to bring the discussion around Open Source practices - that is, the collaboration across organisations to achieve bigger things - to a new audience.
We&amp;rsquo;ve some fantastic speakers lined up from public, private, charity and academic sectors to talk about what being &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; means to them, and how it improves their world.</description></item></channel></rss>