<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Galleries on Coding In The Open</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/</link><description>Recent content in Galleries on Coding In The Open</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-GB</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arfon Smith - Journal of Open Source: Where Open Source meets academic peer review</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/arfon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/arfon/</guid><description>I’m a Staff Product Manager for Data at GitHub, supporting the work of our data science and data engineering teams. Previously, I founded and led the Data Science Mission Office at STScI in Baltimore – the home of Hubble Space Telescope and other flagship NASA science missions. For those of you paying attention, you might have noticed that I was at GitHub once before (2013–2016), helping to bring open source to academia.</description></item><item><title>John A Stevenson - The benefits of engineering national data infrastructure with open source</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/john/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/john/</guid><description>Software developer + postdoc geologist tweeting volcanoes, Iceland, GIS &amp;amp; open source science software. Into climbing, mountain-biking, exploring. Husband, dad.</description></item><item><title>Kirstie Whitaker - The Turing Way: Empowering researchers in reproducible, ethical, inclusive and collaborative science</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/kirstie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/kirstie/</guid><description>Although reproducible research is necessary to ensure that scientific work can be trusted, it requires skills in data management, library sciences, software development, and data ethics considerations: skills that are not widely taught or expected of academic researchers. Beyond these skills lie the structural and incentive barriers to working open. The Turing Way aims to provide a safe space for data scientists in academia, industry, government and the third sector to practice these skills and build open source materials covering version control, analysis testing, collaborating in distributed groups, open and transparent communication skills, and effective management of diverse research projects.</description></item><item><title>Saber Razmjooei - Making a business and a sense of place from open source</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/saber/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/saber/</guid><description>Data is everywhere and without location, it is often difficult to make sense of it. With the free and open source https://inputapp.io you can collect spatial data. The app is powered by QGIS software and allows you a seamless link between mobile and desktop. Synchronisation of the data between the devices and users is done using a git-like technology.
Saber Razmjooei is the Managing Director of Lutra Consulting. Saber has been specialising in Geographic Information System (GIS) solutions including web mapping, geodatabases and desktop GIS for more than 10 years.</description></item><item><title>Sian Basker - TBA</title><link>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/sian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://codingedi.github.io/gallery/sian/</guid><description>Co Chief Exec at Data Orchard. Data maturity, analysis, digital tech, inclusion, equality, social change, fiendish scrabble player, singer, curious explorer.
Data maturity framework</description></item></channel></rss>